[
    {
        "question": "Who has been elected as the 73rd President of the Institute of Chartered Accountants of India (ICAI) for the term 2025-26?",
        "options": [
            "Prasanna Kumar D ",
            "Charanjot Singh Nanda ",
            "Ranjeet Kumar Agarwal ",
            "Ramesh Chandra "
        ],
        "answer": "Charanjot Singh Nanda ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ministry of Health has extended the timeline to small and medium manufacturers having turnover of Rs____ or less for compliance with revised schedule \u2018M\u2019 notification up to December 31, 2025.",
        "options": [
            "Rs 100 crore ",
            "Rs 200 crore ",
            "Rs 150 crore ",
            "Rs 250 crore "
        ],
        "answer": "Rs 250 crore ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which among the following best describes \u2018P-8I Aircraft\u2019, recently seen in the news?",
        "options": [
            "A fighter jet. ",
            "A commercial airliner. ",
            "A stealth bomber. ",
            "A maritime patrol aircraft. "
        ],
        "answer": "A maritime patrol aircraft. ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "S\u1e5bjanam, recently in news, is a:",
        "options": [
            "artificial Intelligence system to curb fake currency notes ",
            "a cloud computing tool to improve service delivery system in India ",
            "new water purifying technology to provide safe drinking water to children ",
            "automated biomedical waste treatment rig "
        ],
        "answer": "automated biomedical waste treatment rig ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to Dokra Artwork, consider the following:  1. It is a form of folk art practiced by the Dhokra Damar tribes.  2. This artwork is mainly found in West Bengal and Odisha region of India.  3. It is done by using lost wax technique.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?  Follow us: Official Site, Telegram, Facebook, Instagram, Youtube 158",
        "options": [
            "1 and 2 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "3 only ",
            "1, 2 and 3 "
        ],
        "answer": "1, 2 and 3 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has won the men\u2019s event at the 91st Billiards and Snooker National Championships 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Pankaj Advani ",
            "Brijesh Damani ",
            "Dhruv Sitwala ",
            "Dhvaj Haria "
        ],
        "answer": "Pankaj Advani ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which institute collaborated with ISRO to develop the \u2018IRIS\u2019 chip for space applications?",
        "options": [
            "IIT Madras ",
            "IIT Bombay ",
            "IIT Delhi ",
            "IIT Kanpur "
        ],
        "answer": "IIT Madras ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organization selected SpaceX for the Pandora mission launch?",
        "options": [
            "NASA ",
            "ESA ",
            "ISRO ",
            "Roscosmos "
        ],
        "answer": "NASA ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is the FAO launching a $95 million climate-resilient agriculture project in?",
        "options": [
            "Somalia ",
            "Ethiopia ",
            "Kenya ",
            "Sudan "
        ],
        "answer": "Somalia ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What percentage tariff has Trump imposed on steel and aluminium imports?",
        "options": [
            "10% ",
            "15% ",
            "20% ",
            "25% "
        ],
        "answer": "25% ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Climate Risk Index, recently in news, is prepared by:",
        "options": [
            "World Meteorological Organization ",
            "World Bank ",
            "UNEP ",
            "Germanwatch "
        ],
        "answer": "Germanwatch ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Indian cricketer has been appointed as an event ambassador for ICC Champions Trophy 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Sachin Tendulkar ",
            "Kapil Dev ",
            "Yuvraj Singh ",
            "Shikhar Dhawan "
        ],
        "answer": "Shikhar Dhawan ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "With reference to J. C. Bose Grant Scheme, consider the following:  1. It is designed to support senior-level researchers who have demonstrated exceptional achievements.  2. It provides an annual research funding of Rs. 25 lakhs for duration of five years.  3. The grant under this Scheme can be availed until the age of 55 years.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 and 2 only ",
            "2 and 3 only ",
            "1 only 3 only  ",
            "1, 2 and 3 "
        ],
        "answer": "1 and 2 only ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding BrahMos NG Missile:  1. It is an advanced supersonic cruise missile developed jointly by India-Russia.  2. It will be able to fit on a wider array of platforms like Sukhoi-30MKI and Tejas fighter aircrafts.  Follow us: Official Site, Telegram, Facebook, Instagram, Youtube 164   Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which State/Union Territory has topped the 2024 \u201cStatus of Devolution to Panchayats in States \u2013 An Indicative Evidence Based Ranking\u201d ?",
        "options": [
            "Kerala  ",
            "Karnataka  ",
            "Tamil Nadu  ",
            "Maharashtra "
        ],
        "answer": "Karnataka  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which institution prepared the 2024 Status of Devolution to Panchayats in States \u2013 An Indicative Evidence Based Ranking report for the Union Ministry of Panchayati Raj?",
        "options": [
            "Indian institute of Public Administration ",
            "TESOL International Association ",
            "National Science Teaching Association ",
            "National Association of Secondary School Principals "
        ],
        "answer": "Indian institute of Public Administration ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Constantine Tassoulas has recently been elected as the new President of which country?",
        "options": [
            "Argentina ",
            "Uruguay ",
            "Finland ",
            "Greece "
        ],
        "answer": "Greece ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the Chief Economist of Canara Bank?",
        "options": [
            "Dr Rajeev Kumar ",
            "Dr Madhavankutty G ",
            "Dr Ramesh Sharma ",
            "Dr Anita Sharma  "
        ],
        "answer": "Dr Madhavankutty G ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which team topped the medals tally at the 38th National Games 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Services Sports Control Board ",
            "Maharashtra ",
            "Haryana ",
            "Karnataka "
        ],
        "answer": "Services Sports Control Board ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state hosted the 38th Summer National Games?",
        "options": [
            "Meghalaya  ",
            "Tripura  ",
            "Uttarakhand  ",
            "Assam "
        ],
        "answer": "Uttarakhand  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state will host the 39th Summer National Games in 2027?",
        "options": [
            "Manipur  ",
            "Meghalaya  ",
            "Odisha  ",
            "Jharkhand "
        ],
        "answer": "Meghalaya  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under the current income tax system in India, what does the term \"Assessment Year\" refer to?",
        "options": [
            "The year in which income is earned. ",
            "The calendar year in which income is assessed. ",
            "The year following the financial year in which income is earned. ",
            "The previous year before the financial year. "
        ],
        "answer": "The year following the financial year in which income is earned. ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the PARAS-2 Spectrograph:  1. It is a fiber-fed spectrograph located at Mt Abu Telescope.  2. It operates in 380-690 nm wave-band and helps in detection of massive planets.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?  Follow us: Official Site, Telegram, Facebook, Instagram, Youtube 174",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which state,President\u2019s rule was imposed in February 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Meghalaya  ",
            "Nagaland  ",
            "Manipur  ",
            "Tripura "
        ],
        "answer": "Manipur  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which state the President rule has been imposed maximum times under the provision of Article 356 of the constitution?",
        "options": [
            "Punjab  ",
            "Jammu and Kashmir  ",
            "Uttar Pradesh  ",
            "Manipur "
        ],
        "answer": "Manipur ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The name of Foy Sagar Lake has recently been changed. In which state is this lake located?",
        "options": [
            "Assam ",
            "Rajasthan ",
            "Tamil Nadu ",
            "Himachal Pradesh "
        ],
        "answer": "Rajasthan ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country was India's new consulate recently inaugurated?",
        "options": [
            "France ",
            "Germany ",
            "Argentina ",
            "Brazil "
        ],
        "answer": "France ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state launched the \u2018Har Khet-Swasth Khet\u2019 campaign to improve soil health?",
        "options": [
            "Punjab ",
            "Uttar Pradesh ",
            "Haryana ",
            "Rajasthan "
        ],
        "answer": "Haryana ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who wrote the memoir 'I Am a Soldier\u2019s Wife: The Life and Love of Toni Lidder'?",
        "options": [
            "Upendra Dwivedi ",
            "Geetika Lidder ",
            "Brigadier LS Lidder ",
            "Toni Lidder "
        ],
        "answer": "Geetika Lidder ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "When is World Radio Day celebrated?",
        "options": [
            "February 12 ",
            "February 10 ",
            "February 13 ",
            "February 14 "
        ],
        "answer": "February 13 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which institution partnered with ERNET India to establish a joint research lab for IoT?",
        "options": [
            "IIT Delhi ",
            "IIT Bombay ",
            "IIITDM Kancheepuram ",
            "NIT Trichy "
        ],
        "answer": "IIITDM Kancheepuram ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "RBI has imposed a penalty of Rs 6.70 lakh on which Small Finance bank for non-compliance with certain directions?",
        "options": [
            "Equitas Small Finance Bank ",
            "Capital Small Finance Bank ",
            "Fincare Small Finance Bank ",
            "Ujjivan Small Finance Bank "
        ],
        "answer": "Ujjivan Small Finance Bank ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "RBI has imposed a penalty of \u20b961.40 lakh on which bank for non-compliance with certain directions on \u2018Interest Rate on Advances\u2019 and \u2018Customer Service in Banks?",
        "options": [
            "Nainital Bank  ",
            "Kotak Mahindra Bank  ",
            "Indian Overseas Bank  ",
            "Canara Bank "
        ],
        "answer": "Nainital Bank  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "RBI has imposed a penalty of Rs 5.80 lakh on which non-banking entity, for non-compliance with certain provisions?",
        "options": [
            "Bajaj Finance ",
            "L&T Finance ",
            "Shriram Finance ",
            "LIC Housing Finance "
        ],
        "answer": "Shriram Finance ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "India and the United States have agreed to double bilateral trade to USD 500 billion by which year?",
        "options": [
            "2028 ",
            "2030 ",
            "2029 ",
            "2040 "
        ],
        "answer": "2030 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "With which country India has launched COMPACT (Catalyzing Opportunities for Military Partnership, Accelerated Commerce & Technology) for the 21st Century\u201d?",
        "options": [
            "France  ",
            "Germany  ",
            "Japan  ",
            "United States "
        ],
        "answer": "United States ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country will sell its Javelin Anti-Tank Guided Missiles and \"Stryker\u201d Infantry Combat Vehicles, to India?",
        "options": [
            "Russia  ",
            "United States  ",
            "Japan  ",
            "Israel "
        ],
        "answer": "United States  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    }
]